<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Copyright (c) 2018 Public Library of Science

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL
THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
-->
<card required-for-submission="true" workflow-display-only="false">
  <DisplayChildren>
    <Description>
      <text>To be of most use to editors, we suggest your letter could address the following questions:</text>
    </Description>
    <Description>
      <text><ul>
          <li>What is the scientific question you are addressing?</li>
          <li>What is the key finding that answers this question?</li>
          <li>What is the nature of the evidence you provide in support of your conclusion?</li>
          <li>What are the three most recently published articles that are relevant to this question?</li>
          <li>What significance do your results have for the field?</li>
          <li>What significance do your results have for the broader community (of biologists and/or the public)?</li>
          <li>What other novel findings do you present?</li>
          <li>Is there additional information that we should take into account?</li>
        </ul></text>
    </Description>
    <ParagraphInput ident="cover_letter--text" value-type="html">
      <text>In your cover letter, please list any scientists whom you request be excluded from the assessment process along with a justification. You may also suggest experts appropriate to be considered as Academic Editors for your manuscript. Please be aware that your cover letter may be seen by members of the Editorial Board. For Research articles, if our initial assessment is positive, we will request further information, including Reviewer Candidates and Competing Interests. For other submission types, if the Reviewer Candidate and Competing Interests cards are already visible to you, please complete them now with the relevant information.</text>
    </ParagraphInput>
    <FileUploader ident="cover_letter--attachment" value-type="attachment" allow-multiple-uploads="true" allow-file-captions="true">
      <label>Attach File</label>
      <possible-value label="doc" value=".doc"/>
      <possible-value label="docx" value=".docx"/>
      <possible-value label="pdf" value=".pdf"/>
    </FileUploader>
  </DisplayChildren>
</card>
