<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Copyright (c) 2018 Public Library of Science

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL
THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
-->
<card required-for-submission="false" workflow-display-only="false">
  <DisplayChildren>
    <Description>
      <text>PLOS journals require authors to make all data underlying the findings described in their manuscript fully available, without restriction and from the time of publication, with only rare exceptions to address legal and ethical concerns (see the PLOS Data Policy and FAQ for further details). When submitting a manuscript, authors must provide a Data Availability Statement that describes where the data underlying their manuscript can be found.</text>
    </Description>
    <Description>
      <text>Your answers to the following constitute your statement about data availability and will be included with the article in the event of publication. Please note that simply stating ‘data available on request from the author’ is not acceptable. If, however, your data are only available upon request from the author(s), you must answer “No” to the first question below, and explain your exceptional situation in the text box provided.</text>
    </Description>
    <DisplayChildren child-tag="li" custom-class="question-list" custom-child-class="question" wrapper-tag="ol">
      <Description>
        <text><div class="question-text">Do the authors confirm that all the data underlying the findings described in their manuscript are fully available without restriction?</div></text>
        <DisplayChildren child-tag="li" custom-class="question-help" custom-child-class="item" wrapper-tag="ul">
          <Description>
            <text>Please see the <a target="_blank" href="http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/s/data-availability" title="PLOS Data Policy">PLOS Data Policy</a> for details.</text>
          </Description>
        </DisplayChildren>
        <Radio ident="data_availability--data_fully_available" value-type="boolean" allow-annotations="false" required-field="false">
          <text>Is the data available as specified?</text>
        </Radio>
      </Description>
      <Description>
        <text><div class="question-text">Your answers should be entered into the box below and will be published in the form you provide them, if your manuscript is accepted. If you are copying our sample text below, please ensure you replace any instances of XXX with the appropriate details.</div></text>
        <DisplayChildren child-tag="li" custom-class="question-help" custom-child-class="item" wrapper-tag="ul">
          <Description>
            <text>If your data are all contained within the paper and/or Supporting Information files, please state this in your answer below. For example, "All relevant data are within the paper and its Supporting Information files."</text>
          </Description>
          <Description>
            <text>If your data are held or will be held in a public repository, include URLs, accession numbers or DOIs. For example, "All XXX files are available from the XXX database (accession number(s) XXX, XXX)." If this information will only be available after acceptance, please indicate this by ticking the box below.</text>
          </Description>
          <Description>
            <text>If neither of these applies but you are able to provide details of access elsewhere, with or without limitations, please do so in the box below. For example:</text>
          </Description>
          <DisplayChildren child-tag="li" custom-class="question-help" custom-child-class="left-indent" wrapper-tag="ul">
            <Description>
              <text>"Data are available from the XXX Institutional Data Access / Ethics Committee for researchers who meet the criteria for access to confidential data."</text>
            </Description>
            <Description>
              <text>"Data are from the XXX study whose authors may be contacted at XXX."</text>
            </Description>
          </DisplayChildren>
        </DisplayChildren>
        <ParagraphInput ident="data_availability--data_location" value-type="html" allow-annotations="false" required-field="false">
          <text>Please describe where your data may be found, writing in full sentences.</text>
        </ParagraphInput>
      </Description>
      <Description>
        <text><div class="question-text">Additional Data Availability information</div></text>
        <CheckBox ident="data_availability--additional_information_doi" value-type="boolean" allow-annotations="false" required-field="false">
          <text>Tick here if the URLs/accession numbers/DOIs will be available only after acceptance of the manuscript for publication so that we can ensure their inclusion before publication.</text>
        </CheckBox>
        <CheckBox ident="data_availability--additional_information_other" value-type="boolean" allow-annotations="false" required-field="false">
          <text>Tick here if your circumstances are not covered by the content above and you need the journal’s help to make your data available.</text>
        </CheckBox>
      </Description>
    </DisplayChildren>
  </DisplayChildren>
</card>
